# Keuntaek Lee

Email:
Website:
LinkedIn:

keuntaek.lee@outlook.com keuntaeklee.github.io

keuntaeklee

I am an applied researcher with 6+ years of research experience in the areas of machine learning and deep learning. My research interests include optimization, probabilistic deep learning, reinforcement learning, optimal control theory, and computer vision.

# EXPERIENCE

Amazon.com

New York City, NY, USA

Applied Scientist II

May 2022-Present

- Research and development on ML/DL for various Amazon products

Honda Research Institute, USA

San Jose, CA, USA

Research Intern at the ML planning and control team  $\,$ 

May 2021–Dec 2021

- ML-based autonomous driving

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA, USA

Research Assistant at the Autonomous Control and Decision Systems Lab.

Aug. 2016–May 2022

- AutoRally: Offroad autonomous driving

- AlphaPilot: Lockheed Martin AI Drone Racing Innovation Challenge

### EDUCATION

## Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA, USA

Ph.D. in Electrical and Computer Engineering, PI: Evangelos A. Theodorou

May 2022

- Thesis: "Robust Deep Vision-based Planning and Control Algorithms with Probabilistic Learning"

## Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, GA, USA

M.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering, PI: Evangelos A. Theodorou

Aug. 2018

#### Hanyang University

Seoul, S. Korea

B.S. in Electrical Engineering (Summa Cum Laude)

Feb. 2016

#### SKILLS

• Languages: Python, C++, MATLAB, SQL, Shell scripting

• ML/DL Tools: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Spark, MapReduce

- Robotics: ROS, CARLA, Mu<br/>JoCo, OpenAI Gym

• Operating Systems: Linux, Windows

## Honors and Awards

Lockheed Martin AlphaPilot Qualifier
 Amazon.com Amazon Web Services Machine Learning Research Awards & Scholarship (75,000 USD)
 RSS 2018 Finalist to Best Systems Paper Award

• South Korea Government Scholarship to Study Abroad (80,000 USD) 2016–2018

• Hanyang Univ. 2nd Prize in Capstone Design Contest 2015

• Hanyang Univ. Dean's List & Scholarship 2013–2015

#### ML-based autonomous driving

Honda Research Institute, USA May 2021–Dec. 2021

- Developed ML-based motion planning and behavior prediction algorithms for safe autonomous driving.
   12% improvement in collision rate compared to SOTA RL methods.
- Keywords: Inverse RL, Planning under uncertainty, Risk-sensitive MPC, LSTM, CNN, VAE, GAN.
- Publications: 1 Journal, 2 Conferences, 2 Patent applications.

AutoRally: ML-based off-road high-speed autonomous driving

Georgia Tech.

Aug. 2016-May 2022

- Developed ML-based motion planning, control, and failure detection algorithms for safe autonomous driving. 62% improvement in obstacle avoidance compared to SOTA imitation learning methods.
- Keywords: RL, MPC, CNN, LSTM, Imitation learning, Bayesian neural networks, System identification,
   Vision-based control, Explainable AI, Uncertainty quantification.
- Publications: 1 Journal, 5 Conferences, 3 Workshops.

AlphaPilot: Lockheed Martin AI Drone Racing Innovation Challenge

Georgia Tech.

Feb. 2019-Dec. 2019

- AlphaPilot Qualifier; Top 9 out of 430 teams worldwide.
- Developed ML-based motion planning algorithms for drone racing. 8% improvement in collision rate compared to motion planning algorithms without ML.
- Keywords: Visual servoing, MPC, System identification, Object detection, Optical flow prediction.
- Publications: 1 Journal, 1 Conference.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- [1] **K. Lee**, D. Isele, E. A. Theodorou, and S. Bae, "Risk-sensitive mpcs with deep distributional inverse rl for autonomous driving", in *IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems* (IROS), Oct. 2022.
- [2] **K. Lee**, D. Isele, E. A. Theodorou, and S. Bae, "Spatiotemporal costmap inference for model predictive control via deep inverse reinforcement learning", in *IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)*, Jan. 2022.
- [3] R. Singh, **K. Lee**, and Y. Chen, "Sample-based distributional policy gradient", in 4th Annual Learning for Dynamics and Control Conference (L4DC), Jun. 2022.
- [4] **K. Lee**, B. Vlahov, J. Gibson, J. M. Rehg, and E. A. Theodorou, "Approximate inverse reinforcement learning from vision-based imitation learning", in 2021 International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), Jun. 2021.
- [5] Z. Wang, O. So, **K. Lee**, and E. A. Theodorou, "Adaptive risk sensitive model predictive control with stochastic search", in 3rd Annual Learning for Dynamics and Control Conference (L4DC), Jun. 2021.
- [6] **K. Lee**, J. Gibson, and E. A. Theodorou, "Aggressive Perception-Aware Navigation using Deep Optical Flow Dynamics and PixelMPC", *IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)*, 2020.
- [7] **K. Lee**, G. N. An, V. Zakharov, and E. A. Theodorou, "Perceptual attention-based predictive control", 3rd Conference on Robot Learning (CoRL), 2019.
- [8] **K. Lee**, K. Saigol, and E. A. Theodorou, "Early failure detection of deep end-to-end control policy by reinforcement learning", in 2019 International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA), May 2019, pp. 8543–8549.

- [9] K. Lee, Z. Wang, B. I. Vlahov, H. K. Brar, and E. A. Theodorou, "Ensemble bayesian decision making with redundant deep perceptual control policies", 18th IEEE International Conference on Machine Learning and Applications (ICMLA), 2019.
- [10] Y. Pan, C.-A. Cheng, K. Saigol, **K. Lee**, X. Yan, E. A. Theodorou, and B. Boots, "Imitation learning for agile autonomous driving", in *International Journal of Robotics Research (IJRR)*, 2019.
- [11] Z. Wang, K. Lee, M. A. Pereira, I. Exarchos, and E. A. Theodorou, "Deep forward-backward sdes for min-max control", The 58th IEEE Conference on Decision and Control (CDC), 2019.
- [12] G. Williams, B. Goldfain, **K. Lee**, J. Gibson, J. M. Rehg, and E. A. Theodorou, "Locally weighted regression pseudo-rehearsal for adaptive model predictive control", 3rd Conference on Robot Learning (CoRL), 2019.
- [13] **K. Lee**, K. Saigol, and E. A. Theodorou, "Safe imitation learning for end-to-end control", in *Robotics:* Science and Systems (RSS) Workshop: Adversarial Robotics, 2018.
- [14] Y. Pan, C.-A. Cheng, K. Saigol, K. Lee, X. Yan, E. A. Theodorou, and B. Boots, "Agile autonomous driving using end-to-end deep imitation learning", in *Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS)*, 2018.
- [15] Y. Pan, C.-A. Cheng, K. Saigol, **K. Lee**, X. Yan, E. A. Theodorou, and B. Boots, "Deep autorally: Agile autonomous driving via end-to-end imitation learning", in *Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS) Workshop on Learning from Demonstrations in High-Dimensional Feature Spaces*, 2017.
- [16] Y. Pan, C.-A. Cheng, K. Saigol, **K. Lee**, X. Yan, E. A. Theodorou, and B. Boots, "Learning deep neural network control policies for agile off-road autonomous driving", in 2017 Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS) Deep Reinforcement Learning Symposium, 2017.

## TEACHING

### Georgia Institute of Technology

• Guest Lecturer in Robotics and Autonomy (AE4803)

Lectures on Differential Dynamic Programming and Model Predictive Control

Spring 2020, Fall 2020

• Teaching Assistant in Feedback Control Systems (ECE3550)

Spring 2019

# ACADEMIC SERVICES

#### Reviewer

• IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)	2019, 2022
• IEEE Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L)	2020, 2021
• IEEE Conference on Decision and Control (CDC)	2019, 2020
• Autonomous Robots (AURO)	2022
$\bullet$ IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)	2021
• Robotics: Science and Systems (RSS)	2019